SATYA TRIPATHI

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Seasoned software developer with more than six years of experience. Committed to providing high-level solutions that drive business and provide outstanding cost efficiency. I specialise in problem identification and proposal of alternative solutions. Highly organised, performance-oriented and customer-driven.

Phone: +91-9654151898
Email: isatyatripathi@gmail.com
Portfolio: isatyatripathi.github.io
LinkedIn: isatyatripathi

Github: <u>isatyatripathi</u>

KEY SKILLS

Back End

- C#, ASP.Net Core Web API 2
- ASP.Net Core MVC, .Net Core 6. x.
- xUnit, NUnit, Specflow, Jest
- Nest.js, Express.js, Node.js v20.x
- LINQ, NuGet Packaging, NPM

Front End

- React.Js, TypeScript, JavaScript
- HTML 5, CSS, Bootstrap
- JavaScript/ES6, RESTful API
- Angular 2+, jQuery

CERTIFICATION

- Microsoft Certified Azure Fundamentals
- Microsoft Certified Azure Developer Associate

Software Development Process

- Agile Software Development
- TDD, Agile, Jira, Scrum
- Microservices, Design Pattern,12 Factor App
- OOP, SOLID principles, SDLC
- VS Code, Visual Studio, Jet Brains

Databases

- CRUD, EF, MS SQL Server, MongoDB
- AWS Aurora, MySQL
- Graph DB, Cosmos DB, T-SQL

DevOps

- Jenkins, Bitbucket, Veracode, Docker
- Kubernetes, SonarQube, Azure, AWS

WORK HISTORY

Senior Software Engineer

Experian

04/2020 - Present

Hyderabad, India

- Developing new product features for the high-volume web application applying knowledge of .NET 6. As a result, 34 bug-free releases have been deployed just in time.
- Creating mature, unambiguous coding standards resulting in overall code base unification and maintainability.
- Performing unit and load testing for the critical online service utilising XUnit and mocking Framework eliminated the system's failure rate by 89%.
- Resolved technical problems relating to the business-critical customers-facing portal, resulting in system performance and scalability improvements.
- Improving product aesthetic and UX of the business-critical progressive web application, resulting in a 73% CHI (Customers Happiness Index) increase.
- Documenting solution architecture for the mission-critical online service, resulting in the system's scalability improvements and reducing the cost of development by 37%.

Systems Engineer

02/2018 - 04/2020

Hyderabad, India

Infosys Limited

- Developed and deployed web applications on Azure cloud platform using .NET Core 3.1.
- Designed and implemented scalable and secure cloud solutions using Azure services such as Azure Functions, Azure App Service, and Azure SQL Database.
- Implemented dependency injection design pattern for building loosely coupled systems.
- Integrating third-party services and external APIs to implement the critical web application, adopting an improved approach that mitigates code duplicity by 49%.
- Conducted performance testing and optimisation of cloud-based applications to ensure high availability and reliability.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to seamlessly integrate cloud-based applications with on-premises systems.

PROJECTS

Experian – Data Accuracy Platform

Full Stack Developer (.Net 6, React, Microservices & AWS)

- It's a product that streamlines Experian's data management by efficiently managing operations, ensuring compliance, maintaining quality, and reporting from diverse sources.
- It's deployed in tailored versions for Experian's Credit Bureaus in the US, UK, Australia, and India with ~43'000 MAU.

Experian – Client Onboarding and Billing Management

Full Stack Developer (Node.js, Nest.js, React, Microservices & AWS)

- It's a product designed to enhance the process of onboarding and managing Clients while ensuring compliance with regulatory checks and risk mitigation.
- Developed with AI integration on Nest.js, React, and AWS, significantly cutting down development and deployment timelines by a factor of 10.

Charles Schwab – Mutual Fund Trading Platform

Backend Developer (.Net 3.1 API, Microservices & Azure)

- It's a modernisation project under the Mutual Funds Trading Platform that empowers fund managers to create and efficiently manage mutual funds.
- Enhanced user experience by integrating various third-party services and external APIs to offer fund comparisons and ratings.

EDUCATION

B. Tech (Computer Science with Specialization in Cloud Computing)
 Galgotias University (2014 – 2018) CGPA: - 8.49

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Won 4 Experian Product Hackathons by designing and implementing robust solutions and showcasing product innovation skills
- Received 12 Experian Spot Awards on different occasions for showcasing better collaboration with varying stakeholders of product for the release
- Awarded with the Rising Star Award for excellence in professionalism and 4 Infosys Insta Awards in a row for excellence in High-quality deliverables and Learning and Adopting new technologies
- Published Paper in IEEE on "Study on a secured framework for cloud-based online banking"